Guide to the Chuck Stone Papers, 1931-2007 and undated RL.01259
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Other Writings Series, 1931-2003 and undated, bulk 1963-2003, 4 boxes
  - Unpublished Writings by Stone Subseries, 1931-1998 and undated, bulk 1967-1998, 2 boxes
    - Movie, 1972, 1983, 1987, 1991 (Box 24)
    - Preaching ideas file, 1990-1991 (Box 24)
    - Stone's Journal
      - Correspondence, contracts, financial documents, and printing information, 1978-1980, 3 folders (Box 24)
    - United Media, 1986-1987 (Box 24)
  - Writings by Others Subseries, 1977-1987, 2001 and undated, 3 folders
    Comprises a graduate student's dissertation manuscript from 2001, and two folders of materials related to the unpublished autobiography of Corinne Huff, former Miss America and mistress to Adam Clayton Powell, Jr. Stone assisted Huff in the planning and possibly also the composition of the autobiography, and the files document that process of collaboration.
    - Frederick, Brian, College Newspaper Ombudsmen, dissertation manuscript, 2001 (Box 24)
    - Huff, Corinne, autobiography manuscripts, drafts, and correspondence, 1977-1987 and undated, 2 folders (Box 24)
- Scrapbooks Series, 1951-1969, 1975, 1985-1990, bulk 1958-1969, 3 boxes
  Series houses the contents of four scrapbooks kept by Stone, disbound for preservation purposes and housed in archival folders. The materials document Stone's media appearances, journalism career, and public relationship with Adam Clayton Powell, Jr. from the 1950s to the end of the 1960s. Each scrapbook deals with a different period of Stone's life, as designated by the bulk dates for each scrapbook, and has been supplied by the archivist with an appropriate name. The first houses clippings, mostly from the New York Age, documenting Stone's time with that newspaper. The second includes clippings, programs, and correspondence collected while Stone was correspondent for and editor of the Washington Afro-American. It also contains several columns by Stone in the New York Citizen-Call, letters by Stone that appeared in the New York Times and The Washington, D.C. Evening Star, and a number of clippings about Stone from various Washington and national newspapers. The third scrapbook houses clippings, programs, leaflets, and a small amount of correspondence documenting Stone's time in Chicago, where he was columnist for and editor of the Chicago Defender and, later, television commentator for WCIU Chicago. The Powell scrapbook documents Stone's activities as press secretary and special assistant to Adam Clayton Powell, Jr. and contains clippings, correspondence, programs, leaflets, and flyers, as well as a folder of miscellaneous articles and media appearances by Stone spanning from the 1960s to 1990.
  Original order of scrapbook pages maintained within each folder. Scrapbooks are listed in chronological order according to bulk dates.
  - 1958-1959, 1965, 1969, bulk 1958-1959, New York Age scrapbook, 6 folders (Box 25)
  - 1951-1967, bulk 1960-1963, Washington Afro-American scrapbook, 6 folders (Box 25)
  - 1963-1965, Chicago scrapbook, 6 folders (Box 26)
  - 1964-1969, 1975, 1985-1990, bulk 1965-1969, Powell scrapbook, 7 folders (Box 27)
- St. Louis Series, 1968, 1986-1997 and undated, bulk 1991-1997, 2 boxes
  Folders contain materials related to Stone's position as Readers' Advocate for the St. Louis Post-Dispatch, where he was hired to oversee their coverage of the mayoral campaign. The series is divided into two subseries, Published Materials and Unpublished Materials, in accordance with the restriction placed on the collection.
  - Published Materials Subseries, 1986-1997 and undated, bulk 1991-1997, 2 boxes
    Includes clippings from St. Louis newspapers, primarily the St. Louis Post-Dispatch, as well as wire service printouts from the time during and immediately preceding Stone's term as ombudsman.
    Arranged alphabetically, then chronologically within.
    - Clippings, 1991-1997 Mar., 6 folders (Box 28)
    - Clippings--Stone's column, 1997 Jan. 12-1997 Apr. 13 (Box 28)
    - Fleishman, Alfred, Sense and Nonsense with Words, undated (Box 29)
    - St. Louis Post-Dispatch wire service printouts, 1986-1989, 1994-1996, 2 folders (Box 29)
    - Wright, John A., Discovering African-American St. Louis: A Guide to Historic Sites, 1994 (Box 29)
  - Unpublished Materials Subseries, 1968, 1996-1997, bulk 1996-1997, 1 box
    Includes unpublished documents and correspondence pertaining to Stone's position as Reader's Advocate for the St. Louis Post-Dispatch.
    - Chuck Stone poll, 1997 (Box 29)
    - Chuck Stone's tabloid survey, 1997 Mar.-Apr. (Box 29)
    - Concerned Citizens for Fairness in the Media, 1996 Dec. 20-1997 Jan. 12 (Box 29)
    - Documents pertaining to the St. Louis Post-Dispatch, 1968, 1996-1997 (Box 29)
    - St. Louis Post-Dispatch correspondence, 1996 Dec.-1997 Mar., 2 folders (Box 29)
- Subject Files Series, 1941-2005 and undated, bulk 1968-2005, 30 boxes
  Houses Stone's extensive files in many different subject areas, consisting primarily of clippings, but also containing notes on the topics and some minimal correspondence. The folders have been preserved as closely to their original order as possible, and Stone's titles have been retained. The exception to this is a set of subheadings that were added to four groups of folders that were physically and topically associated by Stone, and which are of particular interest. These are his files on censorship and the first amendment, on which he intended to write a book ( Free Speech and Jealous Mistresses, unpublished) and taught regularly throughout the 1990s; on the criminal justice system, focused around issues of racism within that system and on Stone's activities as a mediator between the police and inmates or suspected criminals; on the politics and racial bias of standardized testing, an issue with which he became involved while working with the Education and Labor Committee under Adam Clayton Powell, Jr.; and files relating to his academic career, activities, and institutional politics at the University of North Carolina. These can be found under the subheadings Censorship, Criminal justice system, Standardized testing, and UNC respectively. The files on censorship are especially numerous (filling six archival boxes) and contain extensive information on censorship law, types of censorship, and individual instances of censorship. Other topics in this series include black political power in the U.S., minority journalists, women's issues and feminism, affirmative action, religion, electoral politics in the U.S., journalism, multiculturalism and political correctness, higher education, gay and lesbian issues, Philadelphia politics and politicians, and racial politics more generally. There are also significant files on such figures as Mumia Abu Jamal, Jesse Jackson, Martin Luther King Jr., Camille Paglia, Colin Powell, and Clarence Thomas. Subject files relating specifically to Stone's duties as special assistant to Adam Clayton Powell, Jr. can be found in the Adam Clayton Powell, Jr. Congressional Series.
  - Abortion, 1989-2000 (Box 30)
  - Abu Jamal, Mumia, 1995, 2001 and undated, 2 folders (Box 30)
  - Accreditation, 2003 (Box 30)
  - Accuracy in Academia, 2002 (Box 30)
  - ACLU, 2000-2003, 3 folders (Box 30)
  - Adultery, 1997 (Box 30)
  - Affirmative action, 1977, 1995-1999, 2 folders (Box 30)
  - Africa, 1997 and undated (Box 30)
  - African American newspapers (Box 64)
  - Aikat, Deb, 1997 (Box 30)
  - Aikat, Jay, 1997 (Box 30)
  - Arab-Americans, 1991-1995 (Box 30)
  - Ashe, Arthur, 1992 (Box 30)
  - Asian-Americans, 1991-1993 (Box 30)
  - Athletes and the media, 1998-2000 (Box 30)
  - Attribution, 1986-1988 (Box 30)
  - Awards, 2002 (Box 30)
  - Barnett, Claude, file on Stone (Box 64)
  - Bastards [newspaper headline from 2001 Sept. 12], 2001 (Box 31)
  - Bias and racism, 1968, 1990 (Box 31)
  - Bible, undated (Box 31)
  - Black academy, 1968-1970, 1998 and undated, 2 folders (Box 31)
  - Black basketball coaches, 1992 (Box 31)
  - Black books, 1970, 1995 (Box 31)
  - Black College Communication Association, 1998 (Box 31)
  - Black colleges, 1990-1993 (Box 31)
  - Black columnists, 1992 (Box 31)
  - Black conservatives, 1991-1995 (Box 31)
  - Black eloquence, 1993 (Box 31)
  - Black English, 1979 (Box 31)
  - Black experience covers
    - New York Times, 1964, 1969-1970, 1974 (Box 31)
    - Newsweek, 1966-1989 (Box 31)
  - Black fans, 1987 (Box 31)
  - Black feminists, 1994 (Box 31)
  - Black humor, 1997 (Box 31)
  - Black Issues in Higher Education, 1991-1992 (Box 31)
  - Black-Jewish relations, 1967, 1992-1995 (Box 31)
  - Black lawyers, white defendants, 1993 (Box 31)
  - Black leadership, 1970-1988 (Box 31)
  - Black movers and shakers, 2000 (Box 31)
  - Black party, 1968 (Box 31)
  - Black political power in America, 1966-1970, 1986-1987, 3 folders (Box 31)
  - Black political power in America (Box 64)
  - Black politics and black students, 1996 (Box 31)
  - Black Power conference, held 1968 Aug. 29- Sept. 1, 1967-1968 (Box 31)
  - Black Power conference, 1969-1970, 2 folders (Box 64)
  - Black press, 1964-1983, 3 folders (Box 32)
  - Black self-destruction, undated (Box 32)
  - Black studies, 1969-1971, 1994 and undated, 3 folders (Box 32)
  - Black studies, black movies, 1993-1994 (Box 32)
  - Black success stories, 1992 and undated (Box 32)
  - Black survival, 1984-1993, 3 folders (Box 32)
  - Black television viewers, 1986, 1994 (Box 32)
  - Black United Front, 1968-1971, 3 folders (Box 32)
  - Black vote and black presidential candidate: Jesse Jackson, 1983-1984, 2 folders (Box 33)
  - Black-White, 1990-1998, 2 folders (Box 33)
  - Black-white disparity, 2001 (Box 33)
  - Black women, 1991-1993, 1995 and undated (Box 33)
  - Black women publishers, 1993 and undated (Box 33)
  - Black writer's humor, 1996 (Box 33)
  - Blacks and whites, 1992-1993 (Box 33)
  - Bork, Robert, 1987 (Box 33)
  - Boy Scouts, 1992 (Box 33)
  - Brazil, 2001 (Box 33)
  - Broad, Mollie, 1997 (Box 33)
  - Brown, Rite Mae, 1983-1988, 1996-1998 and undated (Box 33)
  - Bruner, Jerome, 1970, 1996 (Box 33)
  - Bush bigotry, 2001 (Box 33)
  - Cancer, 1990-2004 and undated (Box 33)
  - CARE, 2000 (Box 33)
  - Carolina House of Representatives, 1997 (Box 33)
  - Cartoons and art, 1986-1989 and undated (Box 33)
  - Censorship (Box 34)
    - Academic intimidation, 1985-1993, 2 folders (Box 34)
    - Advertisements, 1988-1993 and undated (Box 34)
    - Anti-billboard crusaders, 1991 (Box 34)
    - Anti-pornography, 1989-1993 (Box 34)
    - Armenians, 1995 (Box 34)
    - Art, 1985-1999 (Box 34)
    - Articles, 1988-1990 and undated (Box 34)
    - Automakers, 1996 (Box 34)
    - Banned books, 1984-1986, 1992-2000 and undated, 3 folders (Box 34)
    - BBC's censorship, 1985 (Box 34)
    - Banning of Frankfurt play, 1985 (Box 34)
    - Blacks, 1986, 1991-1995 and undated (Box 34)
    - Book publishers, 1996 (Box 34)
    - Book stores, 1992-1993 (Box 34)
    - Boycotters, 1991-1993 and undated (Box 34)
    - Breast enlargement ads, 2001 (Box 34)
    - Cable TV, 1996 (Box 34)
    - Cartoons, 1994 (Box 34)
    - Catholics, 1995 (Box 34)
    - C*ns*rsh*p, 1985, 1995, 1998 (Box 34)
    - Censorship by intimidation, 2002-2003 (Box 34)
    - Censorship by theft, 1994 (Box 34)
    - Child pornography, 1994-1998, 2000 and undated (Box 34)
    - Clothing, 1995 (Box 34)
    - College newspaper advisors, 1986-1990 (Box 34)
    - College students and administrators, 1989-1994 and undated (Box 34)
    - Commercial speech, 1991-1993 (Box 34)
    - Concurrent censorship, 1994 and undated (Box 34)
    - Conflicting legitimacies between freedom of speech and the prevention of actionable pain, 1993 and undated (Box 34)
    - Constitutionally protected, undated (Box 34)
    - Consumers, 1989-1991 (Box 34)
    - Corporations, 1991-1999 (Box 34)
    - Court cases, 1995 and undated (Box 35)
    - Customs, mores, personal tastes, 1985, 1998 (Box 35)
    - Cyberporn, 1995-1996 and undated (Box 35)
    - Damned in the USA, 1991, 1997 and undated (Box 35)
    - Definitions of censorship, 1998 and undated (Box 35)
    - Dirty lyrics, 1991-1992 and undated (Box 35)
    - Dirty words, 1991-2001 and undated, 2 folders (Box 35)
    - Dirtiest words, 2002 (Box 35)
    - Economics of censorship, 1994-1995 and undated (Box 35)
    - Exceptions to the first amendment, 1997, 2001 (Box 35)
    - Executive branch, 1991-1993 (Box 35)
    - Expletives, undated (Box 35)
    - Fairness doctrine, 1933, 1969, 1985-1987, 1991-1996, 2003, and undated, 3 folders (Box 35)
    - Fighting words, 1995-1996 and undated (Box 35)
    - Finger pictures, 1979-2004 (Box 35)
    - First amendment, 1969-1973, 1983-1994, 3 folders (Box 35)
    - First amendment, racism, and censorship on college campuses, 1987-1989 (Box 35)
    - Foreign censorship, 1982-1985, 1991-1997, 2000-2001, 2004 and undated, 2 folders (Box 36)
    - Free press and fair trial, undated (Box 36)
    - Freedom of speech, 1989, 1993-1995 and undated (Box 36)
    - Gossip, 1995 (Box 36)
    - Government censorship, 1984-2001 and undated (Box 36)
    - Grief, undated (Box 36)
    - Handicapped, 1992 (Box 36)
    - Harvey, Phil, 1994 (Box 36)
    - Hate speech, 1983, 1992-2002 and undated, 2 folders (Box 36)
    - Hate speech vs. hate crime, 1998-2004 and undated (Box 36)
    - Heckling vs. abuse, undated (Box 36)
    - Hollywood reverse McCarthyism, 1992 (Box 36)
    - Holocaust controversy, 1981, 1991-1993 (Box 36)
    - Ideological counter balance, 1985, 1993 (Box 36)
    - Information superhighway and the first amendment, Harvard Law Review, 1994 (Box 36)
    - Internet, 1995-1997 (Box 36)
    - Invasion of privacy, 1890, 1992-1999 (Box 36)
    - Italian Americans, 2002 (Box 36)
    - Japanese Americans, 1993 (Box 36)
    - Jews, 1985-1993 (Box 36)
    - Law and pornography, 1929, 1986-2000 and undated, 3 folders (Box 37)
    - Literature--obscenity, 1991-1992 and undated (Box 37)
    - Louie Louie, 1993 (Box 37)
    - Low value speech, undated (Box 37)
    - Military, 1998-2000 (Box 37)
    - Miscellaneous, 1991-1992 and undated (Box 37)
    - Muslims, 1992-1994 and undated (Box 37)
    - Native Americans, 2000 (Box 37)
    - North Carolina, 1991 (Box 37)
    - Obscenity and the law, 1987-1991 and undated (Box 37)
    - Offensive words, 1985, 1992 (Box 37)
    - Pandering, 1998 and undated (Box 37)
    - Parody, 1993-1994 (Box 37)
    - People for the American Way, 1984-1985, 1994-1996 and undated (Box 37)
    - Pictures--porn, 1968, 1986-1988, 1991-1998 (Box 37)
    - Politicians, 1995 (Box 37)
    - Pornography, 1953, 1966-1969, 1985-2000, 2005 and undated, 8 folders (Box 38)
    - Pornography of sensationalism, 1996 and undated (Box 38)
    - Prayer, 1995, 1997 and undated (Box 38)
    - Presidential censor, 2001 (Box 38)
    - Profanities, 1993 and undated (Box 38)
    - Radio, 1995 (Box 39)
    - Rap music, 1990-2001 (Box 39)
    - Reciprocity of censorship, 1992-1996 (Box 39)
    - Rednecks and KKK, 1996 (Box 39)
    - Religion, 1993-1994 (Box 39)
    - Religious fundamentalists, 1990-2001 (Box 39)
    - Satire (cartoonists, etc), 1984-1991 (Box 39)
    - School principals, 1984-2000 (Box 39)
    - Self censorship, 2004 (Box 39)
    - Self censorship, Ice-T, 1992 (Box 39)
    - Shit, 2000 (Box 39)
    - Speech-Language Association, 1992 (Box 39)
    - Speech on censorship, 1987 and undated (Box 39)
    - Springer, Jerry, 1998 (Box 39)
    - State government, 1995 (Box 39)
    - Stereotypes, 1976, 1994-2001 and undated (Box 39)
    - Student censorship, 1993-1994 (Box 39)
    - Symbols, 1993 (Box 39)
    - Taboo, 1998 (Box 39)
    - Talk shows, 1995 (Box 39)
    - Taste, 1988-1999 and undated (Box 39)
    - Theological thwarters, 1985-1989 (Box 39)
    - Ugly, 1997 (Box 39)
    - Unabomber, 1995 (Box 39)
    - Unholy allies, 1985, 1995 (Box 39)
    - United Nations, 1995 (Box 39)
    - Universities, undated (Box 39)
    - Veterans of World War II, 1995 (Box 39)
    - Violence and the media, 1995, 1999 (Box 39)
    - Voyeurism, 1992 (Box 39)
    - Wildmon, Donald E., 1993 and undated (Box 39)
    - You can't say that, 2001 (Box 39)
  - Character, 2002 (Box 40)
  - Child molestation, 1984-1986 and undated, 2 folders (Box 40)
  - Choice, 1990-1991 (Box 40)
  - Christian Coalition, 1993 (Box 40)
  - Civic journalism, 1997 and undated (Box 40)
  - Clinton, President William J., 1992-1999 and undated, 2 folders (Box 40)
  - Cocaine, 1985 (Box 40)
  - Columns, 1987-1993 (Box 40)
  - Commentaries, 1998 and undated (Box 40)
  - Confidentiality, 1983-1997 and undated (Box 40)
  - Congress, 1995 (Box 40)
  - Congress and taxation, 1994 (Box 40)
  - Congress of African Peoples, 1970 (Box 64)
  - Cops, 1994-1995 (Box 40)
  - Copy editing, 1996-2000 and undated (Box 40)
  - Corporate welfare, 1999 (Box 40)
  - Corruption, 1993 and undated (Box 40)
  - Criminal justice system (Box 41)
    - Bowen, Jo-Jo, 1984-1985 (Box 41)
    - Death penalty, 1983-2000, 2 folders (Box 41)
    - Death penalty and wrongful conviction, 1975-2000 and undated, 2 folders (Box 41)
    - Graterford, 1981, 1985 (Box 41)
    - Hostages, 1977-1990 (Box 41)
    - Miscellaneous, 1978-1999 and undated, 3 folders (Box 41)
    - O'Neill, Francis, 1979, 1990, 1993-1994 (Box 42)
    - Ryder, Edward M., 1982-1987, 1990-1993, 2 folders (Box 42)
    - Summary of wrongful conviction of Beverly Monroe, circa 1999 (Box 42)
    - Surrenders, 1980, 1990-1991, 1997, bulk 1990-1991 (Box 42)
  - Critics, 1995-1998 (Box 42)
  - Critics, cranks, columnists, conflicts of interest, and credibility, 1985-1988, 2 folders (Box 42)
  - Critics of the media, 1992-1998 (Box 42)
  - Crossover generation, 1998 (Box 42)
  - Cuba, 1965, 1994, 2000 and undated (Box 42)
  - Culture, undated (Box 42)
  - Davis, Thulani, 1994-1996 (Box 42)
  - Deafness as a culture, 2000 (Box 42)
  - Debate, 1992 (Box 42)
  - Decalogue, undated (Box 42)
  - Decline and fall, 1984-1985, 1991-1997, 3 folders (Box 42)
  - Democratic Party and the black vote, 1986 and undated (Box 43)
  - Demographics, 2001 (Box 43)
  - Dilemmas in news coverage, 1985 and 1990 (Box 43)
  - Discrimination, 1993 (Box 43)
  - Discussion group, 2002 (Box 43)
  - Diversity, 1987-1999, 5 folders (Box 43)
  - Diversity lecture, 1996, 2002-2003 (Box 43)
  - DMV-NC, 2001 (Box 43)
  - Double consciousness, 1992, 1994 (Box 43)
  - Driving while Black, 1998-1999 (Box 43)
  - Drugs, 1999 (Box 43)
  - Editor and Publisher, 2001 (Box 43)
  - Editorials, 1985-1993 (Box 43)
  - Education, 1990-1994, 2001 (Box 43)
  - Edwards, Senator John, 2000-2001 (Box 43)
  - Electoral college, 2001 (Box 44)
  - Endowed chairs, 1999 (Box 44)
  - Environmentalists, 1992 (Box 44)
  - Ethics in journalism, 1984-1988 and undated (Box 44)
  - Ethnic ambiguity, 1995 (Box 44)
  - Ethnic bashing, 1990-1991 and undated (Box 44)
  - Ethnic puritans, 1983-1994 and undated (Box 44)
  - Ethnic studies, 1996 (Box 44)
  - Ethnics, 1995 and 2001 (Box 44)
  - Everything old is new again..., 1988, 1997 and undated (Box 44)
  - Ex post facto punishment, 1994 (Box 44)
  - Eyesore journalism, 1993-1994 (Box 44)
  - Fair, 2000 (Box 44)
  - Farrakhan, Louis, 1994-1995 (Box 44)
  - Favorite faculty couples, 1998 (Box 44)
  - FCC, 1995-1996, 1999 and undated (Box 44)
  - FBI, 1972-1973 and 1987-1990 (Box 44)
  - FBI, 1963-1999 (Box 64)
  - F.E.A.T., 1988-1990 (Box 44)
  - Feminism, 1992-1995, 2000 and undated (Box 44)
  - Flags, 1989-1994, 1998-2001 and undated (Box 44)
  - Forced expression, undated (Box 44)
  - Ford Foundation, 1991 and 1995 (Box 44)
  - Fortune 500, 2001 (Box 44)
  - Gary, Indiana, 1967 (Box 44)
  - Gay and Lesbian studies, 1994, 1997-1998 and undated (Box 44)
  - Gay militants, 1984, 1991-2000, 2 folders (Box 45)
  - Global classroom, 1995-1998 and undated (Box 45)
  - GOBS-midterm, 1994-1995 (Box 45)
  - Goode, Wilson, 1982-1998, 3 folders (Box 45)
  - Graham, Frank Porter, 1960-1963, 1973, 1995 and undated (Box 45)
  - Graham Child Development Center, 1995-2002, 2 folders (Box 45)
  - Gun control, 1993-1994 and undated (Box 45)
  - Guinier, Lani, 1993 (Box 45)
  - Hair, 2000-2001 (Box 45)
  - Headlines, 1985-1993 (Box 45)
  - Higher education, 1983-1999 and undated, 3 folders (Box 46)
  - History, 2000 (Box 46)
  - Hobson, Julius W., 1968 (Box 46)
  - Homophobia, 1992-1993 and undated (Box 46)
  - Hooker-Buell, Carmen, 1995 (Box 46)
  - Hostages, 1981 and 1996 (Box 46)
  - Humor, 1985, 1992-1997 and undated (Box 46)
  - If mother says she loves you..., 2002 (Box 46)
  - I'm sorry [media apologies and retractions], 2004 (Box 46)
  - Inter-ethnic tensions, 1994 and undated (Box 46)
  - Inter-racial marriages, 1992-1996 and undated (Box 46)
  - Internships, 2001-2002 (Box 46)
  - Investigative journalism, 2002 (Box 46)
  - IQ, 1979, 1985, 1994 and undated (Box 46)
  - IQ and the bell curve, 1969, 1994-1995 and undated (Box 46)
  - Israel, 1988 and 1992 (Box 46)
  - Jackson, Dennis, 1997-1998 and undated (Box 46)
  - Jordan, Michael, 1998 (Box 46)
  - Journalism/ Kerner, 1976, 1986, 1988, 1992-1993 and undated (Box 46)
  - Journalist as public figure, 1956-1987 (Box 46)
  - Journalist students' attitudes, 1990-1998 (Box 46)
  - Kazakhstan, 2002 (Box 47)
  - Kennedy-Lincoln, 2001 (Box 47)
  - Kerner plus 30, 1980-1985, 1991, 1995-2000 and undated, 2 folders (Box 47)
  - King Jr., Martin Luther, 1984, 1992-2003 and undated, 2 folders (Box 47)
  - Knight Commission report, 2001 (Box 47)
  - Knight Foundation, 1993 (Box 47)
  - Komkov, Dmitry, 2001 (Box 47)
  - Kwanzaa, 1996 (Box 47)
  - Last Poets, 1993 (Box 47)
  - Leadership, 1995-1998, 2004 and undated (Box 47)
  - Libel, 1965-1966 and 1983-1995, 4 folders (Box 47)
  - Libel lecture, 1987-1994 and undated (Box 48)
  - Libel-public and private, 1986-1991 and undated (Box 48)
  - Libraries, librarians, and other liberators, 1993, 1999 and undated (Box 48)
  - Lies, 1987-2003 (Box 48)
  - Lite, 1987 (Box 48)
  - Living Legends in Black, 1976 (Box 48)
  - Lumbee Indians, undated (Box 48)
  - Lynchings, undated (Box 48)
  - Magazines, 1955, 1970, 1995, 1998 and undated (Box 48)
  - Malcolm X- Black Beat special 1992 (Box 48)
  - Media, 1959, 1960, 1984-1986, 1991-1999, 2002 and undated, 4 folders (Box 48)
  - Medical deaths, 1999 (Box 48A)
  - Mentally disabled, undated (Box 48A)
  - Militias, 1996 (Box 48A)
  - Minorities media committee, 1990-1994 (Box 48A)
  - Minority journalists, 1993 (Box 48A)
  - Miss America, 1952, 1969-1996 and undated (Box 48A)
  - Moeser, James, 2001 and undated (Box 48A)
  - Movies, 2002 (Box 48A)
  - Multicultural holidays, undated (Box 48A)
  - Multiculturalism, 1963, 1987-1997 (Box 48A)
  - Muslim women, 2001 (Box 49)
  - NABJ, 1972-1975, 1978, 1998, 1990-1993, and 1998-2001 (Box 49)
  - NABJ, 1990s (Box 64)
  - NABJ, 1990s, 3 folders (Box 65)
  - NABJ clippings (Box 65)
  - NABJ memorabilia (Box 65)
  - NAMME, 1990-1991 and 1998 (Box 49)
  - Nation, The, 1985 (Box 49)
  - National Geographic, undated (Box 49)
  - National Society of Collegiate Scholars, 2001 (Box 49)
  - National Urban League conference, 1976 (Box 49)
  - National Writer's Workshop, 2000 (Box 49)
  - Native Americans, 1987 (Box 49)
  - New York Times series on race, 2000 (Box 49)
  - News values, 1997 (Box 49)
  - Newspapers and TV over 30 years, 1991 and 2001 (Box 49)
  - Nightline, 1989 (Box 49)
  - North Carolina Political Review, 2001 (Box 49)
  - Northern Ireland, 1981, 1993-1994, 2000 and undated (Box 49)
  - OFUs-oversized F__ Ups, 1986-1993 (Box 49)
  - Old folks, 1994, 1997-1998 and 2000 (Box 49)
  - Ombudsman, 1984-2003 and undated (Box 49)
  - On being black, 1999-2001 (Box 49)
  - One day on affirmative action, 1995 (Box 49)
  - Oops, 1993-1994 and undated (Box 49)
  - Operation H.O.T., 1991-1995 (Box 49)
  - Outline, 2000 (Box 49)
  - Paglia, Camille, 1992 (Box 49)
  - Peacock [ William H. Gray III], 1988 and 1990 (Box 50)